哥本哈根亚轨道组织 丹麦 众筹预算的业余太空计划
原视频名：Stories in Motion S1 E5- Copenhagen Suborbitals
原作者名：Red Bull
视频来源：www.redbull.com/int-en/episodes/stories-in-motion-s1-e5
原视频发布日期：20210409
字幕翻译：WJIJKKH，校对：旋火
Copenhagen Suborbitals's goal is to send a person into space.
哥本哈根亚轨道组织的目标是将人送入太空
And they are hopefully doing that by the beginning of the 2030s.
而且他们有希望在2030年代初做到这一点
50名航天业余爱好者 一个目标：将一个人送入太空
When we succeed in sending a person into space
当我们成功地将一个人送入太空时
it would show the world it's possible for regular people to do a very technically challenging task.
它将向世界表明 普通人也有可能完成一项非常具有技术挑战性的任务
And also we'll have shown that Denmark has become the fourth nation to send a person to space.
而且我们也将证明 丹麦成为了第四个能将人送入太空的国家
Ignition.
点火
[ENGINES FIRING]
发动机点火
I am the chairman of Copenhagen Suborbitals.
我是哥本哈根亚轨道组织的主席
We're in our rocket workshop just four kilometers from Copenhagen center.
我们现在正在离哥本哈根市中心仅四公里的火箭车间里
In my daytime job, I'm a pricing manager at a sanitary company.
在白天 我的工作是一家卫生用品公司的价格经理
Here, I'm responsible for the design and testing of parachutes used for the space capsule
在这里 我负责设计和测试用于太空舱的降落伞
and the rocket that will bring it to space and safely back again.
以及将把太空舱带入太空并使其全返回的火箭的降落伞
We have engineers, we have artists
我们团队中有人是工程师 有人是艺术家
we have a kindergarten teacher.
我们之中还有一位幼儿园老师
What brings us together is the passion of
把我们聚集在一起的 是这样一种激情
trying to solve the almost impossible quest of sending a person safely to space.
试图解决将人安全送入太空这一几乎不可能完成的任务
I work as a student assistant in the hydraulics department at MAN Energy Solutions.
我在曼恩动力裝置公司的液压部门担任学生助理
Here at Copenhagen Suborbitals
在哥本哈根亚轨道组织
I'm looking into the guidance navigation control subsystem of the Spica rocket.
我正在研究角宿一火箭的制导导航控制子系统
角宿一火箭 长14米 最高飞行速度3600千米每小时 发射时间2030年代初
In daily work I'm a software engineer.
在日常工作中 我是一名软件工程师
Here at Copenhagen Suborbitals I work on mainly electronics, radio communications to and from the rocket
在这里 我的工作是火箭的主要电路以及无线电通信
and some of the electronics support systems on the ground.
以及我们在地面上的一些电子支持系统
Space ought to be accessible for anyone on Earth.
太空应该是地球上任何人都可以进入的
Of course, access to space requires a bit of money
当然 进入太空需要一定的资金
but we're trying to show
但我们正在试图证明
that we can actually do it on a quite limited budget compared to the big players in the market.
与大公司相比 我们实际上可以在相当有限的预算内做到这一点
哥本哈根亚轨道组织预算 10万美元 美国国家航空航天局(NASA)预算 220亿美元
We're crowdfunded.
我们的资金是众筹的
500-600 people all over the world are donating roughly nine thousand euros per month.
世界各地的500到600人 每月共捐赠大约九千欧元
Meaning that we have what corresponds to roughly 10% of NASA's budget for coffee.
这意味着我们的预算差不多相当于NASA咖啡预算的10%
We have to be very creative with what we do, how we do it
对于我们所做的事情 所做的方法
and what we can afford to buy for the rockets.
以及我们能为火箭购买的东西 我们必须发挥最大的创意
In one of the first rockets
在第一批火箭中
we had an urgent need for heat, for a large valve, to avoid it from freezing over.
我们急需热量 以避免一个大阀门被冻坏
So the quick and dirty solution was a hair dryer from a shop in the harbor
因此 临时应急的解决方案是使用了一个来自港口商店的吹风机
that we could use to keep that valve heated.
我们可以用它来保持阀门的温度
One of the first prototypes I had to make for a ballute contained some air vents
我为气球式降落伞做的第一个原型中包含了一些通气口
and I tried to design them so that they were kept open by something.
我试图通过某些设计来使他们保持打开
So in the end I had the idea to use bra underwires.
所以最后我想到了使用胸罩的钢圈
So basically the first prototype I made was of size 75A.
所以基本上我做的第一个原型排气孔的尺寸是75A
气球式降落伞系统测试 2018年
自2011年 哥本哈根亚轨道组织共进行了6次试飞
JDenmark's too small and the population density too high to launch such rockets from land
丹麦太小 人口密度太高 所以无法从陆地上发射这种火箭
which everyone else does.
就像其他国家通常做的那样
最近一次成功的发射 NEXO II火箭 2018年
Fortunately, in the middle of the Baltic there's an old naval training area
幸运的是 在波罗的海中间有一个古老的海军训练区
which has about 2.5 thousand km of flat, uninhabited water
它有大约2500公里的平坦的 杳无人迹的水域
which is a good place to launch from a safety point of view.
从安全的角度来看 那里是一个发射火箭的好地方
We're standing in front of the Nexo II rocket.
我们正站在Nexo II火箭的前面
This is the section where we have the guidance and control computer.
火箭的这一部分里有我们的制导和控制计算机
We have the GPS systems, the power distribution systems and the telemetry systems.
这一部分里有GPS系统 配电系统和遥测系统
This, here, is the fuel tank.
这里 是燃料箱
The fuel is an ethanol-water mix.
火箭使用的燃料是乙醇和水的混合物
We use ethanol not because it's the best rocket fuel
我们使用乙醇并不是因为它是世界最好的火箭燃料
but because it's water soluble and it's not causing any environmental problems.
而是因为它是水溶性的 不会造成任何环境问题
The Nexo class rockets are basically flying laboratories.
Nexo这级火箭基本上是飞行的实验室
It's all a test flight of what we intend to use for the Spica rocket.
它进行的都是我们打算用于角宿一火箭技术的试飞
角宿一火箭将集中过去13年的所有技术
它将把一位航天业余爱好者宇航员送入太空
Spica is going to be launched off the rail
角宿一火箭会沿着发射塔上的轨道被发射出去
and then it'll go supersonic and reach a point where it'll have the engine cut off.
然后 它将以超音速飞行 并达到一个时刻 在那时它的发动机将会关机
At that point, it should go 3600 km/h.
在那一刻 它的速度应该达到了3600公里每小时
And the capsule is going to reach an altitude of 100 km above the earth's surface, which is the Kármán line.
同时太空舱将达到距离地球表面100公里的高度 也就是卡门线
Both the rocket and the capsule will be separated from each other.
火箭和太空舱都将彼此分离
They'll be recovered by parachutes.
它们都将通过降落伞进行回收
I'd very much love to be the one that goes into Spica
我非常希望成为进入角宿一火箭的那个人
and it's also been suggested as a joke in a way
同时 这一举动也会被认为是一个笑话
because I'm the one who wants to work on the guidance navigation control of the rocket
因为我是那个想研究火箭的导航控制的人
I might as well be the person testing it on myself, right?
我也可以成为用自己测试它的人 对吗
And I would probably fit the requirements as well.
而且我可能也会符合进入的要求
So that would be... something.
所以 这将是很了不起的
Why do we do this? We do it because we can.
我们为什么要做这件事 我们做它是因为我们可以
And we want to be able to solve this gigantic, near impossible thing.
并且我们希望能够解决这个浩大的 几乎不可能解决的事情
Amateurs having the possibility of launching humans into space
航天业余爱好者有可能将人类送入太空
is a complete game changer as there's none of the budgets involved
将是一个完全的规则改变者 因为其之中没有任何的财政预算参与
none of the staff involved.
也没有任何专业工作人员参与
If space can become accessible by a number of amateurs doing this
如果太空会因为这些航天业余爱好者所做的事变得容易进入
it's a whole new benchmark for how to get to space.
这将是关于如何进入太空的一个全新的基准